<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Gunnar König</title>
    <link>https://gunnarkoenig.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Gunnar König</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 16 Apr 2022 00:30:03 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://gunnarkoenig.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>If interpretability is the answer, what is the question?</title>
      <link>https://gunnarkoenig.com/posts/2022/interpretability-levels/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Apr 2022 00:30:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gunnarkoenig.com/posts/2022/interpretability-levels/</guid>
      <description>I propose a taxonomy of the types of questions that IML methods can answer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hi! I&#39;m Gunnar.</title>
      <link>https://gunnarkoenig.com/aboutme/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gunnarkoenig.com/aboutme/</guid>
      <description>I am interested in the development of sustainable machine learning and its application for the societal good.
I am a PhD Candidate with Prof. Moritz Grosse-Wentrup and Prof. Bernd Bischl with research interests causality and interpretable machine learning. I&amp;rsquo;m a founding member of ThinkTech (prev. ConsciousCoders), helped start WeRePack and contributed to initiatives like data science for social good.
Before, I did my M.Sc. Data Science at LMU Munich, funded by the elite network Bavaria and my Bachelor at TU Munich.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publications</title>
      <link>https://gunnarkoenig.com/publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gunnarkoenig.com/publications/</guid>
      <description>Papers 2021 Molnar, Christoph, et al.
&amp;ldquo;Relating the Partial Dependence Plot and Permutation Feature Importance to the Data Generating Process.&amp;rdquo;
arXiv preprint arXiv:2109.01433 (2021). [pdf]
König, Gunnar, et al.
&amp;ldquo;Relative feature importance.&amp;rdquo;
2020 25th International Conference on Pattern Recognition (ICPR). IEEE, 2021. [pdf]
König, Gunnar, Timo Freiesleben, and Moritz Grosse-Wentrup.
&amp;ldquo;A causal perspective on meaningful and robust algorithmic recourse.&amp;rdquo;
arXiv preprint arXiv:2107.07853 (2021). [pdf]
König, Gunnar, et al.
&amp;ldquo;Decomposition of Global Feature Importance into Direct and Associative Components (DEDACT).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teaching and Supervision</title>
      <link>https://gunnarkoenig.com/teaching/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gunnarkoenig.com/teaching/</guid>
      <description>Teaching 2022 SS22: Advanced Machine Learning [course]
SS22: Seminar Introduction to Causal Inference [course]
2021 WS21: Seminar Philosophy and Explainable AI, jointly at MCMP and Statistics Departement, [course]
SS21: Seminar Causality and Graphical Models, LMU Munich, [course]
SS21: Current Research in Data Science, LMU Munich
2020 WS20: Seminar Ethics in AI, LMU Munich, [course]
WS20: Seminar: Current Research and Applications in Interpretable Machine Learning, LMU Munich, [course]
SS20: Seminar Causality and Graphical Models, LMU Munich, [course]</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
